Good morning church, for those of you that haven't met me yet, my name is Ryan, one of
the treasures of being one of the pastors here, and I tend to not cry in public, but
this morning might be a test of that, we'll see if else, we'll see how it goes, and this
morning I just feel the weight of the task that I've been given, but then I must preach
peace. In the season that for so many of us doesn't feel very peaceful. For those of
us that life is going as good as it's ever been, let me remind you that Christmas is next
week. So even if you're in a season where life is great, you probably have gifts to buy
and parties to go to and rooms to clean, and if you're anything like me, even in the depths
of circumstances around Christmas, it can be stressful, it can be overwhelming, it can
be filled with anxiety.
But chances are for many of us, life isn't going as good as it should possibly be done. As a matter
of fact, Christmas often excruits some of the most difficult circumstances in our lives. Christmas
often reminds us that loved ones that we wish were here are not here, that family units that
once were together are no longer together. Things that we never set out to be true are true, and we're
reminded of the fleeting nature of peace. I feel the weight of that this morning.
What I believe with all of my heart, what the Scripture says is true, that there is a peace that passes
understanding that is available to each and every one of us this morning, no matter the
circumstances. No matter the difficult circumstances you might be facing right now, there is a peace
that is available to you. And I just wrestled with that this week. And I want to extend that to you in a way that's
accessible, that's not shallow, that's real. And so let's pray and ask for the Holy Spirit to do it each and every one of us to communicate his truth to us in a way that's accessible and real for where we are this morning.
Father, Father, we pray that, over this morning, the Holy Spirit came into the stairs of this room, into the individual's hearts and minds of this room.
As I preach what you've given me to preach on peace, may it be received at the individual level.
May your believers know that peace is available to them, no matter the circumstances after them.
May the people who are not insecure, where they stand with you, or if they even believe that you exist, may they realize that through submitting your life to your leaders, that they might receive a peace that passes all understanding and no matter the circumstances they face.
In Jesus' name I pray. Amen.
Hey, that was heavy. Let's lighten it up a little bit.
How many of you are people that like to change your own oil?
Do me a favor, raise your hand if you're a change-your-own-oil type of person, or if you're the spouse of a change-your-own-oil type of person, raise your hand, awesome, love it.
I've mentioned many times on these days that I'm not a handy person, that I'm not good at doing handy things, but even I have changed my own oil.
Even I have been able to do that, but when we look at Virginia, our garage is like tiny, like my car bear, that's just my garage.
So I move up on the changing of the oil, and I go to one of those rap-a-loop places.
You guys know what I'm talking about?
The three, four, five big garages.
They drive you in, they drive you out, they change your oil, you know what I'm saying?
You also know that they always kind of upsell you on, like, everything that you could ever not need, they try and sell it to you.
And I'm like, I was, I'm a piece of paper, I don't like to say no to people, and so they tend to sell me in their social that I know I don't need.
I'm like, no, thank you, no, thank you, no, thank you, no, thank you.
One time, I was at a rap-a-loop place, and they actually offered to allow you my time.
Okay, here's what I know about rap-a-loop places.
If you never work at one, no offense.
Not the type of people I'm going to trust are on my tires.
I trust them with my oil, because here's the reality.
If they screw up my oil, my hands are going to blow them.
If they screw up my tires, I might blow them, right?
And so there's, like, this level of trust where I'm like, hey, you can change my oil, but please, please, do not change my tires.
And the reason I share this with you at the beginning of a message on peace is because I believe it gives us a helpful framework for where we're heading down a message.
Because as I studied this idea of peace in the Scriptures this week, ultimately, I realized that peace is about alignment.
That true peace comes from our alignment in life.
When we are aligned with the creator of the universe, we can experience peace no matter the circumstances.
Well, our alignment is dependent on who we trust with the leadership of our lives.
And some of us are trusting ourselves or other people or circumstances with the leadership of our lives, and we're never going to experience true peace.
There's always going to be a level of alignment that isn't there.
But ultimately, if we want true, lasting peace that comes no matter the circumstances, it's all dependent on who we align our lives.
Good.
See, in the Bible, peace isn't just about the absence of war, but it's about the presence of something better.
It carries, like, at this idea of complete fullness.
Actually, in the Bible, it can be used, the word flow, peace, it can be used to describe a rough law that's perfectly aligned, without blemets.
It's as the designer intended it to be.
But I have to define peace, biblical peace, learning words.
I would say this, a biblical peace is the experience of creation in complete alignment.
Peace is creation in complete alignment.
Have you ever really felt this deep in your soul?
This might seem like a ambiguous definition, but for me, it's like a few days into a deep vacation, when everything's going right.
When I have enough money saved up for the deep vacation, and everything is going right, there's no dress or difficulty.
There's no relational tension in a filt by the way it's crashing on my feet with my loved ones, and I'm experiencing this feeling of peace.
It doesn't last very long, but I've experienced it before.
Do you guys know about the feeling that I'm talking about?
If we're honest, that feeling often is very sweet and it doesn't last forever long to feel it grasping after a bus in the wind.
And the reason of this is because I believe, and most of us in the media are followers of Jesus Christ,
because we believe that the reason the moments like this don't last very long is because we believe that creation has been thrust out of alignment.
I believe in the garden, they chose to rebel against God's original desire, and his emotion, his alignment for creation.
Everything was good and very good in the garden.
There was relational peace.
There was provisional peace.
There was spiritual peace.
It was all aligned as God intended it to be an avenue that a moment rebelled against God,
and it thrusts all of creation out of alignment.
Scripture says that creation groans and humanity roars as a result of that rebellion,
and you and I, we all experience that sin in rebellion.
We've all made an active intention of a decision to rebel against the creator of the universe,
and because of that rebellion, our peace is fleeting.
It's like grasping at dust.
And when we have moments and glimpses of it, but it's impossible to possess.
It's impossible to possess.
Sounds like that.
Anybody else request yet?
We're going to be good news.
In that moment, when creation was thrust out of alignment,
the God of the universe began a process of restoring all of creation back to eternal,
back to complete alignment, the way that he intended it to be.
It was a process that is going to take way longer than you and I ever would have designed it to take.
It is a process that is perfect.
And his goal is to restore all of us creation so that one day every knee will bow and every tongue will confess that Jesus is Lord.
This process of restoration started the moment that it was thrust out of alignment.
God promised to ease that from the seed of a woman there would come a son who would trust the head of the son.
It started with promises to individuals and covenants with groups of people.
It grew into the establishment of kings and kingdoms.
And the funny thing about the kings and kingdoms part is that wasn't God's plan either, but we continued to prevail.
The nation of Israel said, we want a king like all of the other nations.
And God says, no, you don't.
You want me to be your king.
I'm your king.
This thing will work better if I'm in charge.
And they said, nope.
No thank you.
We want a king like all the other nations.
And so God continued his perfect plan.
Even in the midst of their rebellion, he established kings and kingdoms.
And this process seemingly drug on for thousands of years.
And so the entire plan came into focus in a single night and a little son called the son.
Where a child was born.
A son was given.
A son who would take ownership of the culmination of his plan of restoring peace to all his children.
And he would do the hard and sacrificial work to establish a new type of kingdom.
A spiritual kingdom that will continue to expand and bring alignment to individuals and churches.
And so one day he will return again and finalize his everlasting kingdom.
And creation will be a real life once and for all.
And that feeling of peace will be all that we will ever know.
And I am increasing far better than you are listening to this.
Come on.
This program has been started.
And we've seen glimpses of it all throughout our lives and all throughout the community.
And I know what you're thinking.
Ryan, that's a really inspirational story.
And I believe in it.
And I'm excited for it.
But what about now?
How do I experience peace now in the midst of creation, thrust out of alignment?
How can I experience peace when my desire to sin is so overwhelming?
When so many of my relationships are broken.
When I can't pay my bills and my loved ones are suffering.
How do I experience peace in those moments of my own love, selfishness, and anger, fear, disappointment?
Where is peace found in all of that?
I'm glad, yes.
Because that's the rest of my outline.
If you have your bubbles, I'd love for you to turn to Psalms chapter 23.
This is not a concept that often gets read at Christmas time.
But I think it's a perfect, practical explanation of how you and I can experience peace in the midst of even the most difficult situations and circumstances.
So in chapter 23, starting in verse 1, David said,
David, one of the greatest poets of all time is writing his exclamation, his poetic exclamation of what peace feels like.
This is David's verse that I might be speaking to you.
You guys hear this?
This is David saying, this is what peace feels like.
And he starts out in verse 1 by saying that this peace comes from us trusting the creator of the universe with leadership of our lives.
This is Yahweh, the Lord, he is my shepherd.
Creator God is the one that I follow.
And when I follow to the leader God, Yahweh, he lets me rest in green meadows and leads me beside peaceful things.
When God is the leader of my life, I experience peace.
The more I study peace this week, the more I realize that true alignment is based on who it is that is in charge of being aligned.
And the same reason why I trust the rest of these guys to align my desires is the same reason that you and I assume that anyone or anything has leadership of any area of our life other than the one who made us and who knows what is good.
We know this.
It might seem like an obvious answer, but it isn't that simple.
We might all agree intellectually with the statement.
We might all say yes and amen, but what happens between a pew or a seat at church on Sunday and tomorrow I spend a few?
Things don't go the way that we think it should be going and we say, whoever's in charge of my life right now, they don't get to be in charge anymore.
I'm going to take that control because this isn't working out the way that I thought this would work out.
We don't often, I don't often ask people over to my house because it's very far away and I feel bad asking people to drive holding up them through the woods to pass around the house and go.
That's what it feels like.
And so when people do come over, I try and make it a fun experience.
I had a big bonfire, I was kind of side by side.
And last time people were over, we had a group of young kids and I was letting them kind of clean those drives just side by side along the property.
And one of my favorites, children, Colvin Smith, kid is good at driving.
He's grown up driving stuff, snow carts, lawn mowers, like he, I've got some trust in him to take the wheel of the side by side.
And so I was letting him drive the side by side of him and honestly paying less attention to him than most of the kids because he has experience, he knows what he's doing.
But there was a few moments when we were accelerating faster than I would like and we were heading in a direction that I wasn't really thrilled with and I had this urge in me to do what?
It's the wheel.
And he's like, no, buddy, we're not going there, we're not doing that, we're going on a brake, drift the wheel in the other direction.
And I share this illustration with you because I'm thinking of this as such a clear picture of what we do in our everyday life.
We're headed in a grip.
Things are happening in life that we're not comfortable with.
Things are going on around us and we say, God, I trusted you yesterday, but I'm not sure what you're doing today.
And we grab a hold of the wheel and it's in my pastoral opinion that this is the cycle in our lives that keeps us from experiencing true spiritual peace that passes understanding.
We're following God and things are going well, and then something bad happens.
And we decide the whole following God thing isn't working out anymore, and so we're going to take that control.
And if we're really honest with ourselves, don't we make it worse?
We make it worse, but in the moment, the temptation is, this isn't working out the way that I thought it was going to work out, so let me take back the wheel for a little bit.
I'll give it back to you.
I'll let you have leadership of my life later once I figure out all this stuff going on, once I get myself back in alignment, then you can have control to make it worse.
And David knows this, and he tells us of some obstacles to our peace, some obstacles that make us want to take back control of our lives.
In verses 4 and 5, he's going to say that circumstances, difficult circumstances, and enemies are the two main obstacles that rob us of our peace, that make us want to take the wheel back from God.
When difficult circumstances come into our lives, or when enemies surround us, look at how David says, if he says a better line of word, he says,
Even when I walk through the darkest valleys, I will not be afraid for your close beside me, your rod and your staff protect and comfort me.
David says, Sometimes following your step leads you into dark valleys and difficult circumstances.
Sometimes following Yahweh as your shepherd and your leader leads you through dark valleys, difficult circumstances, sickness, relational stress, financial stress, failures at work or with your kids.
Things just pile up, and it makes you feel like you're in the valleys of the sorrow of death.
We often follow the shepherd until it starts to get dark and difficult, and then we grab a hold of all the wheels.
Financial stress.
We panic.
We stop being generous, and we start to worry and fear, which often leads us to overwork.
Or the opposite.
We have crippling anxiety about what in the world we are going to be, and so we can't even move.
So we self-meditate.
Whatever your form of self-meditation is, you know, I know what mine is, you know what yours is, this is what we do when financial stress comes.
When relational stress comes, we feel hurt, so we get angry.
We lash out against or avoid the people that we love.
Again, self-meditation through screen-gazing, substances, whatever it might be for you.
Physical stress.
We get diagnosed with the sicknesses out of our control.
The baby that we've been training for for years never comes, and we get angry with God.
And we start down a path that leads to bitterness and resentment, and before we know it, I'm sorry.
We're so hard towards the one who has committed us and loved us and wants to lead us through this dark valley and into greener pastures and besides still waters, but we can't get there because our hearts are so hardened.
Spiritual stress.
We fail as a friend, as a spouse, or as a parent.
We're crippled with shame and regret and self-hatred, so we do the same thing that you did.
We have some good.
We know that he can't stand us.
He must be so angry with us.
We believe the lie of the enemy.
Or we do the opposite.
We're trying to put on a good, religious faith.
We're trying to pretend like we're better than we are.
Because we know if God's none of us, maybe we can convince our Christian friends that we're more spiritual than we actually are.
And this is the cycle that throws so many of us out of alignment.
Difficult circumstances arise.
And although we confess that we trust God in reality, we take back control over our lives and we make it worthless.
Romans 8, verse 6 says that the mind governed by the flesh leads to death.
When we trust our own flesh, our own desires, our own feelings, with the government, the leadership of our life, it leads to death.
With the mind that is governed by the spirit, it leads to life and peace.
Who is leading you to these difficult circumstances?
When the valley of the shepherd just finds its way into your life, the response is not to stop following the shepherd.
The response is to remember that the shepherd is the one who at first led you beside still waters and aim to bring your palm trees.
And to know that the shepherd has a plan through the valley to get you back to bring your palm trees.
No promise that comes from the side of his return, but he has a plan.
And we can trust him.
And David knows this.
David was a shepherd.
David had led lots of sheep beside green pastures and through, and besides still waters and aim to green pastures.
And he also had led sheep through dark valleys because he had a plan to get them to the next green pasture, to fill the water, the bigger pasture.
God has a plan.
And David knows that it's in the valley of the shadow of death that we're tempted to take back control.
But he knows that it's in those times we remind ourselves that God is right, and it's God that protects and comfort us.
I don't know what valleys might be facing you today, but I believe with all of my heart that the Lord is a good shepherd who wants to read and see what he's violated.
So if green pastures and the side still waters and again, it might not come in the time that you want it to come, but it will come.
Difficult circumstances are one obstacle to a piece, the second obstacle to a piece, the enemy.
David says, you prepare a piece for me in the presence of my enemies.
You honor me by anointing my head with oil.
My cup ovens words with a blessing.
Surely your goodness and unfailing love will pursue me all the days of my life, and I will live in the house of the Lord.
This is the second biggest obstacle to our piece.
And I know you guys are all more Christian than I mean, and we've never admitted you guys, none of you in here have enemies, right?
So I guess you're too Christian for us.
How are you?
Christ and enemies.
Both physical enemies and spiritual enemies.
Individuals who have betrayed you deeply.
Some of your closest friends, the people that are supposed to be the safest people have betrayed you.
Bosses have taken advantage of you, drop out maybes, drive you nuts.
There's people all around you that are trying to rob you of your peace.
And on top of our sinful enemies, we struggle with spiritual enemies.
The Bible says, let the enemy of God comes to steal, steal, and destroy your peace.
Those enemies will often surround us.
And what happens when we have enemies that surround us?
We want to take that control of our lives.
God, you're not handling this person the way that I would want you to handle this person.
It seems like they're not experiencing the justice that you say you're all about.
I'm the one experiencing the pain.
There's no justice for them.
So why don't I take that control just for a minute, and I'll show them what justice feels like.
And then I'll let you have some soul back.
Anybody?
No.
That's not how peace is experienced.
See, David is writing both as yes and shepherds, but David also has had the experience of being a king.
Look what he says in verse 5.
He says, you prepare a feast for me in the presence of my enemies.
A king is the only person that can prepare a feast in the presence of enemies.
The people all around the nation are looking around, and they say, we're surrounded by enemies.
We've got to start rallying.
We've got to rally the streets.
We've got to get in position.
And oftentimes, the king knows, hey, we've already got a plan for this stuff.
We're going to have victory over these enemies.
You might not see it.
But I know things that you don't know.
I have access to information you don't have access to.
So I can throw a feast in the presence of your enemies because I have a plan for victory.
And David says, this is the type of plan we serve, that even when we feel like we're surrounded,
and there is no hope to be found, there is no victory to be had,
he says, trust the king who has a plan.
The king knows what you don't know.
He has information that you don't have, his thoughts are higher than your thoughts.
His ways are higher than your ways.
You can have peace in the midst of being surrounded by your enemies because God ultimately will bring about justice.
Maybe not the way that you would bring about justice, but I promise you it's going to be better.
Maybe not in the timing that you would bring about justice, but I promise you it's going to be better.
1 Corinthians 15 says, death has been swallowed up in victory.
This is our king, this is his plan.
Where, O death, is your victory?
Where, O death, is your sin?
The sin of death, it's sin, the power of sin, it's the law, but thanks be to God.
He gives us victory through our Lord Jesus Christ.
When all hope for peace seems lost.
And when the valley of the settled death, when we're surrendered by enemies, the response is not to take that control.
The response is to trust yourself to King Jesus, who has overcome spiritual enemies and will bring about ultimate justice.
He's going to the sword of all things to the ways.
There'll be one day, he's going to wipe all their tears from your eyes.
There'll be no mourning.
There'll be no sadness.
There'll be no...
And as we talk about, we light a candle because Jesus is coming and partially established his kingdom.
And one day he's going to establish it.
He met blue or any white clarity to hear from our eyes.
It's no longer going to be a little frame.
But the Bible says that Jesus, the presence of Jesus, will replace the Son.
No more need for the Son as to the moon.
Jesus will reveal once and for all what Jesus was meant to do.
He will bring it to the one moment.
Enemies, come on, trust us from joy.
I think the words have said just perfectly encapsulated this entire message.
You know, I'm not going to specifically to see another Messiah because I wanted to quote this verse in Daniel chapter 3.
When a couple of people who, if you grew up in search, you probably know them lovingly as, um, what is it, Sadrach and Benny?
Is that who it is?
Rad, Sadrach and Benny, there you go.
There you go.
There you go, people.
These people of God.
God's nation have been ripped away from their homeland and been taken into captivity by enemies.
By battle line.
And King Nebuchadnezzar, this evil king that was against the things of God and against the people of God, said,
You are going to have to bow down to my leadership.
Forget the leadership of this God of Israel.
Bow down to my leadership.
Enemy.
Surrounded by enemy.
And this is what the response was.
He said,
If you don't bow down to me, I'm going to throw you into the fire from us.
And this is the response of a few godly people who realize no enemy can rob me of the peace that God has for me.
They said,
King Nebuchadnezzar,
We do not need to defend ourselves before you on this matter.
If we are thrown into the blazing furnace,
the God we serve is able to deliver us from it,
and he will deliver us from it.
These people,
surrounded by enemies in a space to believe that God would provide victory for them in this situation.
But I love the next person.
But even if he doesn't,
we want you to know in the next few days that we will not serve your God or worship the image of God that you have set up.
This is an example for us of what it looks like to submit to the leadership of Jesus.
Even when you're surrounded by enemies,
we trust that he's going to have a breakthrough in this moment,
in this situation,
that he's going to provide victory for my enemies here and now.
But even if he doesn't,
we know that he ultimately will.
And so we walk into the fire
knowing
that surely your goodness and my healing ones are consumed.
In all the days of my life,
I will dwell in the house of the Lord forever.
I love how him,
I would all dismiss places.
He says this,
In the secret of God's tabernacle,
or God's presence,
no enemy can find this.
No troubles can reach them.
The pride of men and the stress of sons find no entrance in the pavilion of God.
People that are much older than me
just know a better way of using words than I do.
It's a very good time.
It's incredible.
He says,
I do not mean that no trials come.
They may come in abundance,
but they do not penetrate the sanctuary of the soul.
We may dwell in perfect peace
in the midst of life's fiercest storms.
Let me tell you what happened to Shadrach,
and Frank and Abednego.
Did God deliver them from the sons?
No.
He went with them and missed them.
He was delivering his words of the presence
in the midst of the most difficult circumstances.
Believer,
if you're being here,
you're struggling for peace.
I don't know exactly what it looks like for you,
but I believe that the presence of God
is what he made with.
Yes, he can deliver you,
but even if he doesn't,
his presence is enough.
Genuine biblical peace
that alignment
that we were intended for
comes from submitting ourselves to God.
There's a shepherd
who leads us through difficult circumstances
and king
who prepares a peace for us
in the midst of our enemy.
Experiencing peace on earth
in the midst of signs
is all about who we trust
with the leadership right now.
We're going to start to conclude by reading
the verse that I'm supposed to read
at Christmas time.
I don't know if you.
Isaiah chapter 9
says this,
for to us a child is born.
To us a son is given
and the government
will be on his shoulders
and he will be called
wonderful counselor,
mighty government,
everlasting father
and prince
of peace
and of the greatness
of his leadership,
his government
and peace
will be known
and he will reign
on David's throne
and over his kingdom
establishing it
and upholding it
with justice
and righteousness
from that time on
and forever
the zeal
of the Lord Almighty
will accomplish this.
Isaiah 9 prophesies
of the original
climates
that God made to me
or that God made to Eve
in Genesis chapter 3.
I'm going to send the son
who's going to cross
the head of the serpent.
The son has been born.
He has established
his kingdom
and his kingdom
is expanding.
His government,
his rule
is expanding
and will continue
to expand
until one day
he returns
once and for all
and spits
on his eternal throne
establishing peace
and justice for all.
This passage
was already begun
to be fulfilled.
An infant
born in Bethlehem
and a couple thousand years later
you and I will sit
in this room
in northern Virginia.
It's his government.
It's his reign
expanding.
Two billion plus
Christians
are a result
of this baby
being born
in Bethlehem.
Not because he was
just born
but because he would
live a perfect
sinless life
and he would die
in your place
for your sins
and all of that
is beautiful
and wonderful
but it means
nothing apart
from an empty team
he has victory
over sin,
death,
and the grave.
Victory over any
difficult circumstances
you might have.
Hebrews says that
in every way
he understands
the difficult circumstances
that he files
and temptations
that we face
and yet he did not sin.
the moment
the reason
was crossed
out of the line
that God
began to pray
for real
and it was
when he was
praying
from the birth
of Jesus
to see the woman
that would trust
the head of the
faith
and has been
born
and his student
has been
established
and is
expanding
where you trust
to him
with the leadership
of your life
to the home.
It's your only hope
for true
and understanding
peace
in the midst
of a broken
world.
This is what
the Christian lives
is all about.
There is submitting
every area
of your life
to the leadership
of Jesus.
There is becoming
far more patriotic
to the kingdom
of God
than any kingdom
this world
has to offer
or any kingdom
you have to find
blessing.
In just a minute
we're going to
celebrate some baptism.
Baptism is such
impressive way
to end this message.
This is that to me
is a picture
of these individuals
telling you publicly
I'm submitting
my life
to the lordship
of Jesus
to the leadership
of Jesus.
He has his way
in every area
of my life.
We have a church
we doctored
in two different ways
and both of them
are symbols
of us bowing
in reverence
and submission
to the leadership
of Jesus.
When we doctored
people forward
in this same
I'm bowing
my life
in submission
to the Father
the God
the Son
and God
the Holy Spirit
and when we
baptized backwards
they said
I must guide
to my old life
and I've been raised
to be life
in Jesus.
Those pictures
have submitted
to the leadership
of Jesus.
So if you're in here
and you've never
submitted your life
to the leadership
of Jesus
I invite you
to do so today.
You're here right now
because God is
drawing you
to who he says
Jesus.
sitting at your
attention
this morning
and you
in your chair
today
since Jesus
I invite you
to have
leadership
for my life.
If you are brave
and you want to
make that decision
today for the first
time
come up and get
baptized
we've got foes
we've got vows
we've got you covered
as you feel
the Lord
draw on you
to submit
your life
to his
readership
for the first
time today
coming back.
If both of
those things
are too intimidating
and you're not
serving for it
understanding what
this whole thing
means come
ask the Lord
through these
two times
I'm going to
be one of our
readers as well
to talk to you
about what it
looks like to
submit your life
to the readership
follower of Jesus
are you ready
to see your
face with you
because I'm
stepping on my
information
what area
of your life
are you holding
on to what
you're doing
what areas
of sin
are you refusing
to let God
work on you
in your finances
is it an
addiction
is it bitter
influence
or unforgiveness
against some
area of self
distinction
in your life
and ask God
to reveal to you
what are the
areas of your
life that you're
still holding
on to the
readership of
your life
many of us
are in the
midst of the
darkest valleys
and we're
surrounded by
enemies
and it feels
hopeless and
chaotic and
unnatural
urges to
grab all the
readership of
our life
I keep
with you
this morning
don't buy
the lies
of your
name that
says you're
a better
reader
Jesus is a
better
reader
his ways
are harder
than all
ways
his paths
are all
in the
others
and we
should make
ours
his leadership
amen
after
pray
those
of you
that are
being
baptized
to come
forward
and I
pray
here
in just a
minute
and ask
the
worship team
to come
back up
and lead
us in
this song
another
and another
Messiah
saying it's
just a great
response to
what we've
heard here
this morning
that we
might walk
through dark
valleys
we might be
surrounded by
enemies but
God will
meet us
his presence
will dwell with
us in the
midst of the
fire
his presence
will be with
us and his
presence will
bring us
peace
no matter
the circumstances
of our lives
but we're
going to
actually do
something
different
we're going
to worship
while we
baptize
worship is
a celebration
of what God
is doing
and has done
us bringing
to God
and receiving
his blessings
over us
and celebrating
what God
has done
in the
individual's
lives
we're going
to do
that
we're going
to stand
to worship
we're going
to sing
and when we
baptize
people
if you
don't yell
louder
than you're
going to yell
at your TV
later this afternoon
when your
favorite team
scores itself
down
then maybe
maybe you
are like
to take
that leadership
as it is
in your life
we celebrate
this morning
new life
in Jesus
renewed life
peace
that causes
understanding
let's pray
Father
thank you so
much
for the
peace
that you
offer us
for the
leadership
that you
give
to our
lives
your
kingdom
has been
established
and will
continue
to be
established
until one
day you
will return
and make
everything
of us
you will
like
the way
of
research
in our
lives
it will be
nice
peace
for morning
sickness
or sadness
we will only
know
the experience
of creation
and align
with your
God
that until
that day
comes
may we be
clean
in your
presence
in the midst
of our
darkest
valleys
and only
feel like
we're
surrounded
by
love
may we
feel
in your
peace
in Jesus
name
amen